BENJAMIN CORNEJO COSTAS

Address: Utrecht, The Netherlands | Mobile: +31651452282 | Date of birth: 22/04/1988 | Email Address: bcornejocostas@gmail.com | LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/benjamincornejocostas

PROFILE

Economics and development policy specialist with more than 8 years working in the public and private sector and in international organisations. Experience in managing and executing national and international public policies in science, technology, and innovation and currently finalising a PhD in Economic Geography focusing on green regional diversification and development.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Sep 2020 – Present | PhD Candidate and MSC Actions fellow in Economic Geography, University of Utrecht, Utrecht, The Netherlands.

• Research on skills, regional development and green diversification.

Apr 2023 - Oct 2023 | Rabobank Research | External Researcher

• Production of a policy report article on water calamities and their impact on sustainable-environmental water-related technologies.

Feb 2020 - Aug 2020 | Grupo Vi-DATEC S.A. | Talent Manager

- IT skills course contents responsible in a startup.
- Coordinate a team to deliver the courses.
- Deliver the business model and plan the execution of the product.

Dec 2019 - Jan 2020 | Embassy of the Argentine Republic, London, United Kingdom | STIP advisor

 Advisor on the bilateral cooperation strategy between the United Kingdom and Argentina regarding science, technology and innovation policies through science diplomacy. Researched in trends of emerging technologies and business opportunities in technology.

Jul 2019 - Aug 2019 | OECD-OCDE, Paris, France | Intern

- Research on trends and estimated data series of STIP Compass database in the Directorate of Science Technology and Innovation. Used network analysis to predict point of contacts.
- Wrote policy-brief reports on the STI policies in Argentina. Benchmarked with other countries for country reviews.

Feb 2017 - Jul 2018 | Ministerio de Producción de la Nación, Buenos Aires, Argentina | National Coordinator

- Manager of a group of 25 to deliver a national innovation policy on IT skills.
- Negotiation with all stakeholders to ensure the governance of the policy and the delivery of the policy to the main clients: IT companies

EDUCATION

Sep 2020 – Present: PhD Candidate and MSC Actions fellow in Economic Geography, University of Utrecht, Utrecht, The Netherlands.

• Feb 2021 – Jun 2021: Academic secondment at Bocconi University in Milan, Italy, to attend advanced econometrics courses and conduct my research on talents, human capital and green innovations.

Sep 2018 - Sep 2019: MSc Science and Technology Policy, SPRU, University of Sussex, Brighton, United Kingdom

May 2015 - Oct 2017: MPP Public Policy and Administration, Universidad de San Andrés, Buenos Aires, Argentina

Mar 2006- Dec 2011: BA in International Relations, Universidad Católica de Salta, Argentina

PROFESSIONAL TRAINING

- 2023 | Text Mining | INGENIO (CSIC) Valencia Polytechnic University. Valencia, Spain.
- 2022 | Text Mining | INGENIO (CSIC) Valencia Polytechnic University. Valencia, Spain.
- **2022** | Start to teach | Utrecht University, Utrecht, The Netherlands
- 2021 | Econometrics | Bocconi University, Milan, Italy
- 2021 | Presenting with impact | Utrecht University, Utrecht, The Netherlands
- 2020 | Data Science | Digital House, Buenos Aires, Argentina

SKILLS

Languages | English (Fluent), Spanish (Native), French (Intermediate), German, Portuguese, Dutch & Italian (Basic)

IT | Microsoft Outlook, Word, Power Point, Excel and Project; Google Suite; Trello; Python: Pandas (Advanced) |

Stata; R (Intermediate) | HTML (Basic)

INTERESTS AND ACTIVITIES

Tennis | Running | Cycling | Travel | Coding